Frank Liu

I am a Ph.D. Student at Arizona State University, advised by Robert Likamwa in the Meteor Studio. I am interested in enhancing human computer interaction experiences through mixed reality and machine learning, advancing education and encouraging overall health and wellness. I enjoy working on projects that incorporate my diverse skillset in signal processing, physical prototyping, machine learning and human-computer interaction.

PhD Candidate
Electrical, Computer &
Energy Engineering
Arizona State University
Tempe, AZ

Website

fwliu1.github.io

Email

fwliu1@asu.edu

EDUCATION

PhD Computer Engineering, Arizona State University

2018 - Present Advisor: Robert Likamwa

BS Electrical Engineering, University of Washington

2014 - 2018 Advisor: Hanchuan Li, Shwetak Patel

HONORS & AWARDS

Dean's Fellowship, Arizona State University

- Awarded to top 4% of admitted graduate students with significant leadership and research capabilities Ira A. Fulton Fellowship, Arizona State University

Priscilla and Melvin Wilson Endowed Scholar, University of Washington Electrical Engineering Departmental Honors IEEE HKN Honors Society, University of Washington

- Scholastic achievement in the top 30% of graduating class Husky Leadership Certificate, University of Washington

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

- P2 SWISH: A shifting-weight interface of simulated hydrodynamics for haptic perception of virtual fluid vessels Shahabedin Sagheb, Alireza Bahremand, **Frank Liu**, Assegid Kidane, Robert Likamwa ACM UIST 2019, New Orleans, Louisiana
- P1 A Spatial Audio System for the Internet-of-Things

Frank Liu, Robert Likamwa

Hotmobile 2019, Santa Cruz, California Awarded: NSF Student Travel Grant

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Summer 2018 National Taiwan University - IoX Center, Gongguan, Taiwan

Research Intern. Mentor: Professor Bing You

Award of Excellence: Significant contributions in shipping android application SoberComm, allows alcohol

dependent individuals and their family members to monitor alcohol usage

Spring 2018 Roxy Device, Seattle, Washington

Startup Intern.

Lead generation and public outreach for customer acquisition. Built, assembled, and QA tested Roxy Device

hardware systems.

Winter 2018 Microsoft, Redmond, Washington

Consultant.

Created labs, lessons and course content for the "Introduction to Device Programming" EDX (MICROSOFT COURSE) [DEV295X] using Microsoft's IOT Pack for Raspberry Pi for audience of thousand+ students

Spring 2017 Verizon Wireless, Bellevue, Washington

Systems Performance Intern.

Supported Systems Performance/Radio Frequency engineers in evaluating and improving areas of poor

coverage using internal SP / RF tools

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University

Arizona State Spring 2019: Teaching Assistant for AME 394, "Introduction to Mixed Reality"

University of Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Spring 2018: Grader and Teaching Assistant for EE215,

Washington "Introduction to Circuits"

Coding with Kids Spring 2017, Classroom Instructor

Taught coding course curriculum for scratch at local elementary schools.

SERVICE

Reviewer Mobisys 2019

Volunteer TEI 2019

Mentor Summer 2019, Advanced Robotics at the University of Washington

Member Fall 2017 – Spring 2018, The College of Engineering Student Advisory Council

Interviewed students and faculty about mental health on campus and prepared a recommendation report

to improve student well-being on campus.

INVITED TALKS

Scholar-Donor From my exemplary leadership and service on campus, I was personally invited by Michael Bragg, Dean of the College of Engineering, as a speaker for the 2017-2018 Scholar-Donor Recognition Luncheon.

SELECTED PRESS

Sunhacks State Press. Sunhacks provides an inclusive outlet for ASU students

Advanced Robotics at the University of Washington

UW Daily. Robotics team breaking down obstacles... literally

Seattle Times. These attack robots and their UW creators will take on the world at RoboMaster competition

in China

Seattle Times. UW students and their attack robots hit bumps in China — then a hotel hair dryer saved the

day

Bloomberg. China's High-Stakes Robot Wars

REFERENCES

Robert Likamwa likamwa@asu.edu

Shwetak Patel shwetak@cs.washington.edu